Finding aid for the Paulist Productions records LSC.2300
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2. Capital Cities specials, 1977-1988
  - It Can't Happen to Me [#805], 1977-1978 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    Two scripts by Richard Fielder; publicity material.
  - It Can't Happen to Me [#805], 1979 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    Photographs; motion picture film frames.
  - Josie [#815], 1980-1983 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    Three scripts by Jim Moser [two annotated]; publicity material.
  - Josie [#815] - photographs, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 6-7)
  - The Juggler of Notre Dame [#820], 1982 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    Three scripts by Lan O'Kun.
  - The Juggler of Notre Dame [#820], 1982 (Box 66, Folder 2-3)
  - Leadfoot [#808], 1982 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    Two scripts by Jim McGinn; publicity material; photographs.
  - Loser Take All [#803], 1977 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    Script by Terry Sweeney; script by Mike Rhodes and Terry Sweeney; publicity material; photographs.
  - Princess [#810], 1979-1982 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    Two scripts by Jim McGinn [one annotated]; publicity material; photographs.
  - Rocco's Star [#823], 1982-1983 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Rocco's Star [#823] - photographs, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - 17 Going on Nowhere [#813], 1980-1981 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    Two scripts by Jim McGinn [one heavily annotated]; publicity material; photographs.
  - Soupman [#812], 1983 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    Two scripts by Lan O'Kun [one heavily annotated]; publicity material.
  - Soupman [#812] - photographs, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - A Step Too Slow [#816], 1981 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    Two scripts by Jim McGinn [one heavily annotated]; publicity material; study guide; photographs.
  - This One for Dad [#804], 1977 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - This One for Dad [#804] - photographs, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - To Climb a Mountain [#817], 1981 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - The Trouble with Grandpa [#818], 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder unknown container)
    Four scripts by Lan O'Kun; photograph; publicity material.
  - When, Jenny, When? [#806], 1978 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    Three scripts by John Farrell [one annotated].
  - When, Jenny, When? [#806], 1978 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Who Loves Amy Tonight? [#814], 1981 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Two scripts by William P. McGivern [one heavily annotated]; publicity material; photographs [includes off-camera shots of Laura Dern].
  - Publicity and reviews, 1979-1988 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    Includes report on Nielsen ratings; photographs.
  - Study guides, 1978-1983 (Box 69, Folder 3-5)
  - Subseries 1. Scripts
    This subseries consists of scripts that had been bound together in numerical order. Many of the scripts include editing notes, and some include production documents.
    - Productions #803-805, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Productions #806-808, 1978-1979 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Productions #814-816, 1980-1981 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Productions #817-819, 1981-1982 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Productions #820-823, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Productions #824-825, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 3)
- Series 3. Reflections, 1976-1985
  This series contains material on films produced between 1977 and 1984 under the "Reflections" banner. Many of the Reflections titles were broadcast as Capital Cities specials and, if that was the case, they are filed in that series rather than here.
  - The Bet [#827], 1984 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Two scripts by Thomas Chehak [one annotated]; study guides.
  - Clayfeet [#826], 1983-1984 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    Two scripts by James E. Moser [one heavily annotated]; study guides; photographs.
  - The Pilot [#829], 1984-1985 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    Two scripts by Kenneth Berg; study guides.
  - Safe Harbor [#828], 1984 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    Treatment; two scripts by Kenneth Berg; production packet; study guides.
  - The Sex Game [#801], 1978 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    Two scripts by Lydia Wiggins; study guides; photographs.
  - Things Are Different Now [#802], 1976 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    Two scripts by Mike Rhodes [one annotated]; study guides.
  - Things Are Different Now [#802] - photographs, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
- Series 4. Bloomin' Human Films, 1974-1977
  This series contains material on a set of short films intended for exhibition in middle schools.
  - After Dark [#705], undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
    Two scripts [no writer credited]; study guides; photographs.
  - America, a Picture in My Mind [#701], undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Anna and Poppy [#707], 1976 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    Treatment by Terry Sweeney; script by Charles Pavlich; script [no writer credited]; study guides; photographs.
  - Billy's Mime [#702], 1974-1975 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    Treatment by Terry Sweeney & Eva Lothar; script [no writer credited]; study guides; photographs.
  - Desert Trek [#708], 1976 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    Four scripts by Terry Sweeney, S.J. [two annotated]; study guides; photographs.
  - Earphones and Goggles [#711], 1977 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    Two scripts [no writer credited]; study guides; artwork.
  - Get Used to Me [#709], 1976 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    Three scripts by Lan O'Kun; photographs; study guides.
  - The Mouseman [#704], 1976 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    Two scripts by Lan O'Kun; study guides; photographs.
  - My Main Man [#703], 1975 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    Three scripts by Mike Rhodes and Terry Sweeney, S.J.; photographs.
  - The Promise [#710], 1977 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    Treatment and four scripts by Terry Sweeney, S.J. [one annotated]; study guides; photographs.
  - The Secret [#712], 1976-1977 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    Script [no writer credited]; study guides; photographs.
  - The Secret [#712] - photographs, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - A Song of Beauty [#706], 1975 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Catalogs, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
- Series 5. Values: Educating for Responsibility, ca. 1976
  This series contains material on a set of films designed to help teachers educate their students about values.
  - Scripts - segments 1-12, undated (Box 73, Folder 1-4)
  - Photographs - color transparencies, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 5-6, Box 74, Folder 1-2)
- Series 6. Buchanan High, 1984-1985
  This series contains material on a television series, but there is no evidence that it ever aired.
  - Deadline [#831], 1984-1985 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    Two scripts by Josef Anderson [one heavily annotated]; study guide; photographs.
  - Editor and Chief [#830], 1984-1985 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    Two scripts by Tom Chehak [one heavily annotated]; study guide.
  - The Great Chastity Experiment [#832], 1984-1985 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    Two scripts by Kenneth Berg [one heavily annotated]; study guide; photographs.
  - The Loyal Opposition [#833], 1984-1985 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    Two scripts by Lan O'Kun [one heavily annotated]; study guides; photographs.
- Series 7. Miscellaneous productions, 1979-1987
  This series contains material on films not falling under one of the other Paulist Productions banners.
  - Blessed Be [#901], 1979-1980 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Script [no writer credited]; study guides; photographs; motion picture film frames.
  - The Fourth Wise Man, 1984 and 1994 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    Two scripts by Tom Fontana, based on a short story by Henry Van Dyke; letter from Warner Bros. Television.
  - The Fourth Wise Man - budgets, undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - The Fourth Wise Man - clippings, 1985 (Box 75, Folder 4-5)
  - The Fourth Wise Man - photographs, undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - The Fourth Wise Man - publicity, 1985-1986 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    Includes press kits, study guides; transcripts of television interviews with Ellwood Kieser.
  - The Fourth Wise Man - research, 1958-1959 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    Includes "The Story of the Other Wise Man" by Henry Van Dyke [two copies; one annotated; photocopies]; "The Innkeeper's Wife" by A.J. Croning [photocopy].
  - The Fourth Wise Man - storyboards, undated (Box 75, Folder 9-10)
  - Romero, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    Script [no writer credited].
  - We Are the Children, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    Outline; script by Michael de Guzman.
  - We Are the Children, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Two scripts by Michael de Guzman; 8" floppy disk.
    RESTRICTED ACCESS: Use of electronic/digital format material requires special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing.
  - We Are the Children, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    Contains script supervisor's script, with wardrobe Polaroids included.
  - We Are the Children - photographs, 1984-1986 (Box 76, Folder 5-7)
    Includes off-camera shots of Ally Sheedy and Ted Danson; photographs of Ethiopian famine victims.
  - We Are the Children - publicity, 1987 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Whatsoever You Do [#902], 1981 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    Photographs; study guides.
- Series 8. Unrealized productions, 1971-2000
  This series contains material on projects that appear not to have reached fruition.
  - A Brotherhood of Angry Hearts, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
    Script by Harley Mims.
  - Close Feelings - Sexual Encounter: Who, Why, When?, undated (Box 77, Folder 4)
    Two scripts by "Ralph" [one handwritten].
  - DMZ - notes and outlines, 1984 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - DMZ, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
    Script pages ["Hurricane Alley"] by Merrit Malloy [annotated].
  - DMZ, 1984 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    Three scripts ["The Tenderloin"; one annotated; no writer credited].
  - DMZ, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    Outlines by Richard Fielder.
  - DMZ, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    Two scripts by Richard Fielder.
  - DMZ, 1986 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    Script by Richard Fielder [annotated].
  - DMZ, 1986 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - DMZ - correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    Includes drafts of agreements for a television series with ABC.
  - Feelings - outlines and treatments, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 4-5)
  - In a Rotten Little Corner of the World, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
    Script by Harley James Mims.
  - Intimacy, 1987-1989 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    Outline; first draft script by Vickie Patik; notes from Bud Kieser.
  - Intimacy, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    Second draft script by Vickie Patik; notes from Bud Kieser.
  - Intimacy, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    Third draft script by Vickie Patik.
  - Intimacy, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    Fourth draft script by Vickie Patik; handwritten note from Patik.
  - Intimacy, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    Teleplay by John McGreevey, from a story by Ellwood E. Kieser and McGreevey; agreements with McGreevey.
  - Intimacy - agreements, 1987-1990 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    Includes agreements with writer Vickie Patik.
  - Intimacy - correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    Includes outline for a television series; correspondence between Bud Kieser and producer Freyda Rothstein.
  - The Mill Valley Miracle, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    Script by Lan O'Kun.
  - No Child of My Time, undated (Box 80, Folder 4)
    Script by Lydia A. Pepeskul.
  - Not Much -- Just So, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    Outline by O'Connell Driscoll.
  - "Parenting series", 1977-1978 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    Includes series proposals; sample script by Lan O'Kun.
  - Sanctuary, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    Script by Anthony Lawrence [annotated].
  - A Scream from the Brink, undated (Box 80, Folder 8)
    Script by Tom Caramagno.
  - Sex Games, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    Script by Ralph Phillips.
  - Stripping, undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
    Outline by John McGreevey.
  - The Thieves, undated (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Things Are Different Now, 1976 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    Script by Mike Rhodes.
  - The Wizard of Egg, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    Script by D.A. Zodrow.
- Series 9. Father Ellwood "Bud" Kieser, ca. 1937-2000
  This series contains material about or belonging to the founder of Paulist Productions.
  - Africa, 1980-1981 (Box 59, Folder 1, Box 81, Folder 1-2)
    Includes: photos of Kieser's trips to Mauritania, Djibouti, Kenya, and possibly Ethiopia. He was accompanied by John Amos, Levar Burton, Patty Duke Astin, and Dick van Patten; photos of Kieser and Amos testifying before the U.S. Congress; an article by Kieser about the trip.
  - Cast portraits, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
    Contains portraits of Kieser posing with the casts of various productions.
  - Clippings, 1979-2000 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - El Salvador - photographs, 1994 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    Contains snapshots from Kieser's work, with Raul Julia, as an election observer.
  - Europe - photographs, ca. 1970 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    Contains snapshots of Kieser's wide-ranging trip to Europe, from Scandinavia to the Mediterranean.
  - Hollywood Priest, 1991 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    Reviews and publicity material regarding Kieser's autobiography.
  - Humanitas Prize, 1980-2000 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    Contains brochure; periodicals with articles about the prize; photographs of Kieser with Joseph Dougherty, Aaron Sorkin, Henry Winkler, and others.
  - India and Bangladesh - photographs, 1979 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    Contains snapshots and negatives from Kieser's visit.
  - Japan - photographs, 1971 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    Contains snapshots of Kieser's trip, including Nagasaki Peace Park
  - Manuscripts, ca. 1967-1999 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    Contains writings by Kieser that were either unpublished or for which publication information is not provided.
  - Offices - photos, undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
    Contains color negatives and one print of the Paulist Productions offices at 11575 Pacific Coast Highway, which had been the residence of Thelma Todd.
  - On-set photographs, 1962-ca. 1996 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    Contains off-camera shots of Kieser with the actors and crew on various productions.
  - Periodicals with articles on Kieser, 1978-1994 (Box 82, Folder 6, Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Personal items, 1956-1995 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    Includes card commemorating Kieser's ordination; visa for the Soviet Union; WGA pension plan statement.
  - Photographs, ca. 1937-1983 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - portraits, ca. 1965-1991 (Box 59, Folder 3, Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - transparencies, 1978 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Posthumous files, 2000 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    Includes a handwritten letter from Kieser describing the discovery of his colon cancer; obituaries and tributes; copies of faxes to Melinda Dillon and Martin Sheen with readings for the memorial service.
  - St. Paul, 2000 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs and post cards of images of St. Paul in New York City, Washington, D.C., and various books.
  - Staten Island, ca. 1972 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    Contains photographs of Spanish Camp, the community where Dorothy Day had lived.
  - Talk shows - photos, 1962-1978 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    Includes photographs of Kieser being interviewed with Irene Dunne, and by Regis Philbin & Sarah Purcell and Mike Douglas.
  - Writings, 1950-1999 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    Includes published essays by Kieser, ranging from his college newspaper to occasional editorials in the Los Angeles Times.
  - Photographs - unsorted transparencies, 1981-1984 (Box 85)